<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>haicen.me (Posts about IoT)</title><link>https://blog.haicen.me/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://blog.haicen.me/categories/iot.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2023 &lt;a href="mailto:haicenhack@protonmail.com"&gt;Haicen&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 13:36:39 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Auditing a $50 Security Camera DVR System</title><link>https://blog.haicen.me/posts/auditing-a-security-camera-dvr-system/</link><dc:creator>Haicen</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;FYI, this is a rewrite of some work I did in 2016 and was previously hosted on my old blogspot account. In doing research for the rewrite, I found that several people had done largely similar work, but I have identified some new information, particularly the ability to &lt;strong&gt;format the disk drive by sending a post request&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section id="introduction"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the Internet of Things (IoT) took over, homes and businesses were watched by closed circuit cameras, and some did have LAN and WAN remote viewing. The WAN connection was not through a cloud system, but rather a direct connection to the IP address of the device. Unfortunately, given the price point of these devices, a lot of security corners were cut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a whim, I ordered one of these devices (it was on sale at Newegg for $50). The specific device was from &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.newegg.com/shieldeye-rscm-0704b042-4-channel-kit-solution/p/N82E16881147043?Item=N82E16881147043"&gt;Newegg&lt;/a&gt;, (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20210319155009/https://www.newegg.com/shieldeye-rscm-0704b042-4-channel-kit-solution/p/N82E16881147043?Item=N82E16881147043"&gt;Archive.org backup&lt;/a&gt;). It had a lot of neat features (night vision, motion detection based recording, 720p resolution), but I mostly bought it because I wanted to see just how bad the security was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id="project-scope"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Project Scope&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal is to emulate an attacker could disable or delete recordings with no knowledge of the system (i.e. no physical access to the device or model numbers), with the assumption that the attacker is already on the same network as the device. If that isn't successful, the scope will be revised to assume attacker knows the model number of the device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.haicen.me/posts/auditing-a-security-camera-dvr-system/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (14 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>hacking</category><category>IoT</category><guid>https://blog.haicen.me/posts/auditing-a-security-camera-dvr-system/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 15:21:26 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>